它会扯破衣服
Wow. That ripped.
一点也不含糊
That ripped real nice!
你要我说几次？要侧身滑出来
How many times do I have to tell you? You turn and slide.
侧身滑出来
Turn and slide.
不是侧身滑出来
You don't turn and slide.
是把它扔出去
You throw it out!
我每次穿衣服 都得打破伤风预防针
I get tetanus shots every time I get dressed!
不能扔掉，这是我亲手钉的
We're not throwing it out. I built it with my own hands!
好，那卖掉呢？
How about we sell it?
好吧
All right.
不过你得告诉它们
But you'll have to tell them.
你们可以搬个家吗？ 看来它们没意见
Can we stick you in another cabinet? They seem all right with it!
本集播出：“灵猫”
The One with the Cat
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
鸡为什么从树下掉下来？ 为什么？
Hey,why did the chicken fall out of the tree?Why?
因为你头上有鸡屎
Because you have doody on your head.
班说就很好笑
Yeah,it was funnier when Ben told it.
莫妮卡，我是奇普 漂亮！
Hey,Monica. It's Chip.
谁是奇普？
Who's Chip?
很高兴今天遇见你
It was good running into you today.
我的电话是5559323 打给我，就这样
My number is 555-9323. Give me a call.
奇普就是奇普马修斯
"Chip" is Chip Matthews.
瑞秋的高中舞会舞伴？
The guy who took Rachel to the prom?
他打给你干什么？
Why's he calling you?
我在银行遇见他，他还是好帅
Because I ran into him at the bank. He is still so cute.
你好幸运 他是全校最红的男生
You're so lucky! He's like the most popular guy in school!
我知道
I know!
奇普？我是莫妮卡
Chip? Hi,it's Monica.
好…好
Okey,Okey…
好
Okey…
好，再见
Okey,Goodbye
天哪，我们聊得好愉快
Oh,my God! We just had the best conversation!
我正要走
I was just leaving.
好
Good.
我要看报告
I've got a report to read.
有八页，但愿我不会睡着
It's eight pages. I hope I don't fall asleep.
为什么？是你写的？
Why? Did you write it?
看看
Look at that!
奇普马修斯打电话来 不晓得有什么事
Chip Matthews called. I wonder what he wants.
其实…
Well,actually....
他一定感应到 我可以跟别的男人上床了
I bet he sensed that I was ready to have sex with another guy.
那你何不打给他？
Why don't you give him a call?
好啊
Okey
你真的想听？ 真的
-Are you sure you want to hear this? -I'm sure.
奇普，我是瑞秋
Chip! Hi,it's Rachel.
瑞秋格林
Rachel Greene.
你留言给我？
You left me a message?
没错，是你，我的室友记下来了
Yes,you did. My roommate wrote it down.
莫妮卡盖勒？
Monica Geller?
原来如此
Oh,that's right!
他是要约莫妮卡
He called to ask out Monica.
真是尴尬
That's got to be embarrassing.
醉醺醺的白痴贱人
Dumb drunken bitch
谢谢
Thank you!
请问一下
Here's a question.
密西西比以东 最好的橡木家具在哪里？
Where'd you get the "finest oak east of the Mississippi"?
你先说 全国最漂亮的蕾丝在哪里
First tell us where you got the prettiest lace in the land.
这是你们的广告
It's your ad.
不赖吧？
Looks good?
“高级视听娱乐柜，精致…”
"Stunning entertainment center,fine
“精致意大利手工”
Fine ltalian craftsmanship."
天哪，你们要卖娱乐柜？
You're selling the entertainment center?
为什么？我喜欢那个柜子
Why? I love it.
你们要吗？
-You want it? -No.
不要
No
盖比特（《木偶奇遇记》中制造匹诺曹的木匠）
Gepetto?
“定价5千”？
Five thousand dollars?
你疯了吗？
Are you insane?
登广告就要3百
The ad alone cost $300.
我要改成50元或再议
I'm changing it to $50 or your best offer.
那有什么利润可言？ 你也配当会计师？
What kind of profit is that? And you call yourself an accountant?
我不是
No…
那你是干什么的？
What do you do?
你居然不知道我干哪一行
I can't believe you don't know.
我也不知道 是不是什么…
I actually don't know.
天哪，不要，走开 不要…
Oh,my God,no! Shoo,kitty!
甘瑟，我的吉他盒里有一只猫
There's a kitty in my guitar case.
嘘…其他人都想要
Everyone's gonna want one.
给我过来
Come on,you!
真是的
Crazy!
天哪
-Oh,my God!
什么？
-What?
没事
Nothing.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我只是…
I just…
我只是有一股强烈的感觉 这只猫是我妈
I just have this really strong feeling that this cat is my mother.
莫陶克那个妈妈？
The mom you met in Montauk?
她是一只猫？
She was a cat?
而她居然拥有滨海小屋
That makes the fact that she owns beach-front property all the more impressive.
不，她是一个人
No. She was a human lady.
这是莉莉妈妈的灵魂 自杀的那个
This is the spirit of my mom,Lilly. The one that killed herself.
是她变成一只猫 还是你又偷吃外婆的青光眼药
Have you been taking your grandmother's glaucoma medicine again?
没有，疑心博士
No,Dr. Skeptismo.
我很肯定 第一，我有这个感觉
I'm sure. First of all,there's the feeling.
还有，她跑进我的吉他盒里
And for another,she went into my guitar case...
它的衬里是橘色的
...which is lined with orange felt.
我妈最喜欢的鱼是橘棘鲷（又名罗非鱼）
My mother's favorite fish was orange roughy.
猫喜欢吃鱼
Cats like fish.
你让我以为是跟橘色有关呢
You had me with orange felt.
嗨，妈咪
Hi,Mommy!
我17年没看到这个笑容了
I haven't seen this smile in 17 years.
菲比的妈有一对儿好大的… 算了吧
-Phoebe's mom's got a huge pair of -Let it go!
你什么时候要告诉我 你要跟奇普约会？
When were you going to tell me that you're dating Chip?
现在？
Now?
我跟他约会没关系吧？
Can I go out with him?
当然有关系 他那样对我耶
No. I can't believe you'd want to after what he did to me.
你是说舞会的事？
That thing at the prom?
莫妮卡，我2个小时找不到他 他跑去跟艾美威许做爱
I couldn't find him for hours! He was having sex with Amy Welsh!
那是高中的事 你怎么还会在意？
That was in high school. How can it still bother you?
说得也是，莫母牛
Oh,yeah,you're right,Moni-cow.
我懂了
Okay,I hear you.
你为什么偏要跟奇普约会？
Why do you have to go out with Chip?
我们的高中不一样
We went to different schools.
少来，我们上同一所高中
We went to the same school.
你在高中是风云人物
You went to one where you were popular.
你坐奇普的摩托车 穿他的优秀运动员选手外套
You rode on Chip's motorcycle and wore his letterman jacket.
我穿的是特制的乐队制服
I went to one where I wore a band uniform that was specially made.
那是特制的？
They had that specially made?
那是大家的家政课的作业之一
It was a Home Ec project.
天哪 他们说那是给球队吉祥物穿的
Oh,my God! They said it was for the mascot.
那时候我以为 我永远不可能跟奇普约会
Back then I thought that I'd never get to go out with a Chip Matthews.
现在他打来约我
Now he's called me up and asked me out.
我心中那个胖女孩真的很想去 这是我欠她的
The fat girl inside me really wants to go. I owe her this.
我从不让她尽情的吃
I never let her eat.
你去吧 真的？
-You go out with him. -Really?
如果可以，你能不能丢下他 去跟别人做爱？
If possible,could you leave him and have sex with another guy?
我试试看
I'll try.
娱乐柜卖得怎样？
Any luck getting rid of the entertainment center?
昨晚有几通询问电话 但我都觉得不可行
There were a couple calls,but they won't work out.
乔伊有一套严格的筛选过程
Joey has a very careful screening process.
并非每个人都适合拥有木制品
Not everyone is qualified to own wood and nails.
别挣扎了
Stop it!
她一直想跑走 跟在世时一样
She keeps trying to get away. Just like when she was alive.
你妈要跟我们在一起多久？
How long is your mom going to be with us?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
直到她能接受我有了…
I guess until she gets used to the fact that there's...
新妈妈吧
...a new mom.
她很担心会被取代
Now she's worried that she'll be replaced.
才不会呢，对不对？
That's not going to happen,is it?
我去房里回个电话
I have to go make a call.
怎么不在这里打？
Why not use this phone?
我要打给住在B-E-A-C-H（海边）的妈妈
I'm returning a call from a certain mom at the .
我说错词了
I just spelled the wrong word.
我不想在有尾巴的人面前打
Anyway,I don't want to do it in front of someone with a tail.
你发誓不说的
Hey,you swore you would never tell.
是我疯了，还是有人也觉得 菲比的妈是一只猫？
So am I crazy,or does Phoebe's mom remind anyone else of a cat?
罗斯，别提了 拜托
Ross,don't start.
你们真的相信 那只猫是一个女人变的？
You actually believe there's a woman inside that cat?
我相信
I believe it.
你才不信
No,you don't.
我信
Yes,I do.
你才不…
No,you
你知道吗？
You know what?
我不会跟你争辩
You won't suck me into this.
你会 你总是要说服别人
Sure I will. Because you always have to be right.
我才没有…好
I do not always have Okay,okay.
“侏罗纪公园”是有可能发生的
Jurassic Park could happen.
还有 我觉得柯克船长比史波克聪明（星际迷航中的角色名）
And you know what? Actually,I do think Kirk was smarter than Spock.
刚才你说柯克和史波克的那句是开玩笑吧？
You were kidding about the Kirk-Spock-thing,though,right?
还不赖嘛
That's pretty nice.
还不赖？
"Pretty nice"?
原谅我的室友 他简直想娶它
Pardon my roommate. He wanted to marry this.
我们没有50块钱 你们愿意交换吗？
We don't have $50. But would you trade for it?
我们有一艘独木舟
We got a canoe.
我们不需要独木舟
I don't think we need a canoe.
你们一定要收下独木舟
You got to take it.
你们就把柜子搬走吧
Just take the entertainment center.
等你们到家，再把独木舟扔掉
Then when you get home,throw the canoe away.
想都别想，那是我亲手造的
We're not throwing it away. I built it.
干得好！
Good for you!
（中央咖啡馆）
你们看我在电线杆上发现什么
You won't believe what I found on a telephone pole.
眼熟吗？
Look familiar?
显然菲比的母亲也叫胡立欧
Apparently Phoebe's mother also goes by the name "Julio."
不一样吧，这只只有这么大
Wait a minute. This is not the same cat. This cat's only this big.
有个小女孩在找这只猫 知道这代表什么吗？
A little girl's looking for this cat. Know what that means?
知道，五个人平分2百元赏金
Yeah! $200 reward split five ways!
要告诉她吗？
Do we have to tell her?
当然要告诉她 但她现在好开心
-Yes,we do. -But it's made her so happy.
想念猫咪的小女孩
Little girl misses her cat.
觉得猫是母亲转世的疯婆子
Crazy lady thinks her mother is in a cat.
好，我要去跟我儿子吃饭
I have to go have dinner with my son.
你们见到菲比会告诉她吧？
Can I trust that when you see Phoebe,you will tell her?
会
Yeah
谢谢
Thank you.
我最讨厌罗斯说对了
I hate when Ross is right.
他说得对，对吧？
He is right,isn't he?
搞不好这一次他错了
This might be one time when he's wrong.
是吗？
-You think?
不，他说得对
-Oh,no. He's right.
菲比，关于你的母亲… 怎样？
About your mom.
你们处得好吗？
How's that going?
棒呆了，我们今天一起睡午觉
So great. We took a nap together today.
妈在我肚子上睡着还打呼
Mom fell asleep on my tummy and purred.
真温馨
That's so sweet.
我去点咖啡
I'm gonna get some coffee.
乔伊你说什么？我马上过去
What'd you say,Joe? I'll be right there.
菲比 我觉得好…
I just feel so....
知道了啦 马上来
-All right! -I'm coming already!
还没还没还没…
Not yet,not yet,not yet!
奇普 瑞秋，你好吗？
-Hello,Chip. -How you doing?
很好
I'm great!
我有一份好工作，一群好朋友
Got a great job. I have wonderful friends.
虽然现在没有男朋友 却对自己很满意
Though I'm not seeing anyone now,I've never felt better about myself.
莫妮卡好了吗？
So,Monica ready yet?
她马上就好
She'll be out in a second.
奇普，艾美威许好吗？
So,Chip,how's Amy Welsh?
艾美威许？我一直没见她，自从…
Amy Welsh? I haven't seen her since
莫妮卡快好了吗？
So,Monica about ready?
你好漂亮 谢谢
-Wow,you look great. -Thanks.
好好去玩吧
-Well,you guys have fun.
再联络 奇普再见
-Catch you later.-Bye,Chip.
你真的不在意？
-Are you sure you're okay about this?
其实… 太好了
-Actually…Okay,great.
买这个柜子就对了
This is the unit for you.
坚固耐用，容量超大
Sturdy construction,tons of storage.
甚至塞得进一个大人
Some big enough to fit a grown man.
什么？ 对，我就进去过一次
-What? -Yeah,I got in there myself once.
我的室友赌5元说我进不去
My roommate bet me $5 I couldn't.
然后在门把上塞棍子把我关住
Then he stuck a board through the handles and locked me in.
起先很好玩，后来感觉像棺材
It was funny till I felt like it was a coffin.
你才进不去，它不够深
No,you can't fit in there. It's not deep enough.
是吗？
Oh,yeah?
要是我进不去…
If I can't...
就少算你5块钱
...I'll knock $5 off the price.
就这么说定 好
All right,you have yourself a deal.
你看，我就说吧
See? I told you.
有时我会进进出出的玩
Sometimes I come in here just to get away from it.
有5分钱
Hey,a nickel!
到了
Here we are.
天哪，你的奇车还在
You still have the Chipper!
什么？
The what?
那是你的车子在高中的外号
That's what we called your motorcycle in high school.
摩托车也叫机车
A motorcycle's a chopper.
而你叫奇普
And you're Chip.
没事
Never mind.
真可爱
I think it's cute.
奇普亲亲
A lipper from Chipper.
你还有跟哪些同学联络？
Are you still in touch with anyone?
有瑞秋，还有…
There's Rachel...
就这样，你呢？
...and that's it. How about you?
我还在跟西门斯、萨纳混 也常跟史宾、莱文、凯利见面
I still hang with Simens and Zana. I see Spindler,Levine,Kelly.
三不五时会遇见高第
I run into Goldie...
史迪、布朗、苏卡夫、麦奎尔
...Stick,Brown,Sulkov,McGuire...
杰弟、毕斯利
...J.T.,Beardsley.
就这样？
Is that all?
毕了业都会失去联络
After high school,you kind of lose touch.
我有遇见李察多夫曼
I ran into Richard Dorfman.
他好吗？ 不太好，我和西门斯把他内裤拿出来使劲拉
-How is he? -Me and Simens gave him a wedgie.
他不是建筑师吗？
Isn't he an architect?
建筑师也要穿内裤
They still wear underwear.
天哪！
Oh,my God!
怎么了？
What?
你还好吗？ 还好
Are you all right?
怎么回事？
What happened?
他答应不拿沙发椅的
Oh,man,he promised he wouldn't take the chairs!
你怎么会被关进去？ 我们的东西呢？
How were you locked in? Where the hell is all of our stuff?
有一个人来看柜子
This guy came by to look at the unit...
他说它塞不下一个大人
...and he said it won't fit a grown man.
所以你自愿进去？
So you got in voluntarily?
我想把柜子卖出去
I was trying to make a sale!
要是让我碰上他 你猜我会怎样？
If I ever run into him,you know what I'll do?
把屁股翘起来？
Bend over?
萨纳干脆让另一个破掉
And then Zana just let one rip!
我不是不喜欢回忆往事
Not that I don't enjoy talking about high school...
我喜欢
...because I do.
但我们可以聊点别的
Maybe we can talk about something else.
像你，我还不晓得你的工作
I don't know where you work.
你知道啊 我知道？
-You know where I work. -I do?
电影院啊，你以前常来
The movie theater. You used to come in all the time.
你还在影城做事？
Still at the Multiplex?
我怎么可能换工作
Like I'd give up that job!
随时都有爆米花和糖果可吃
Free popcorn and candy anytime I want?
我可以帮你拿海报
I can get you posters.
谢谢，不用了
Thanks,I'm set.
你猜那天谁来了？彼得斯
Oh,you know who came in the other night? Peters.
他说他刚才跟莱斯利・马斯金约会，上了三垒
Told me he just went out with Leslie Maskin. Got to third base.
你还住在家里？
Do you still live with your parents?
对，但是我可以在外面想待多晚待多晚
Yeah,but I can stay out as late as I want.
少了别的东西 柜子就没那么大了
You know,with all of our stuff gone,the unit doesn't seem that big.
那个人怎么不是绑匪？
Why couldn't he have been a kidnapper.
他们还真是大搬家 电视、沙发椅
They really got you guys. Your TV,the chairs.
微波炉、音响
Your microwave,the stereo.
天哪，他把黑桃5拿走了
Man,he took the five of spades!
在这里
No,here it is.
天哪！怎么了？
Oh,my God! What happened?
乔伊出生 28年后，我被抢了
Joey was born,and then 28 years later,I was robbed!
怎么样？
So how was your date?
我高中时一直想跟奇普约会
Well,I always wanted to go out with Chip in high school.
今晚 我真的跟“高中时的”奇普约会了
Tonight,I actually went out with Chip in high school.
真可惜
Honey,I'm sorry.
不会，我不但跟奇普约了会
Not only did I get to go out with Chip...
我还甩了他
...I got to dump Chip.
太棒了 我知道
-That's so great! -I know.
保险公司怎么说？
What did the insurance company say?
他们说 “你们没投保，别再打来了”
They said,"You don't have insurance. Stop calling us."
你们没有告诉她？
You didn't tell her?
好吧
Okay,fine.
菲比
Pheebs
听我说
Listen...
这只猫是一个小女孩的
...this cat belongs to a little girl.
路上贴满了寻猫启事
There are flyers all over the place.
对不起亲爱的
I'm sorry,sweetie.
我们可以陪你把猫送回去
We can take her back with you if you want.
但是她选择来找我
But,you know,she chose to find me.
我得尊重她的决定，对吧？
I have to respect her decision,right?
有道理 没错
-That's a good call. -That's right.
不对，别再闹了
Enough is enough.
我很遗憾你跟新妈妈在一起 会有罪恶感
I'm sorry you feel guilty about spending time with your new mom.
但这不是你的旧妈妈
But this isn't your old mom.
这是一只猫
This is a cat.
它叫胡立欧
Julio the cat.
不是妈妈，是猫
Not Mom! Cat.
罗斯，你失去过几个父母？
Ross,how many parents have you lost?
零个
None.
那你就无法体会 其中一个回来的感觉，对吧？
Then you don't know how it feels when one of them comes back.
我相信这是我的母亲
I believe this is my mother.
就算不是又怎样？
Even if I'm wrong,who cares?
你就当个好朋友，支持我
Just be a friend,okay? Be supportive.
对不起 好
I'm sorry.Okay.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
你可以向她的妈妈道歉
You could say...you're sorry to her mom.
我想她会接受
I think she would like that.
过来，过来
Come here. Here,come here.
布菲太太？
Mrs. Buffay?
我为我说的话道歉
Sorry about what I said.
我实在很伤人
It was insensitive of me to say...
说你只是一只猫
...that you were just a cat...
很显然的，你也是…
...when,clearly,you are also...
我朋友的母亲…
...the reincarnated spirit...
灵魂转世
...of my friend's mother.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们都原谅你
We both forgive you.
那个小女孩怎么办？
What will you do about the little girl?
好，听我说
Listen.
妈，你对我还是很重要
Mom,I hope you know you still mean a lot to me.
你随时都可以回来
You're welcome to come back anytime.
菲比
Pheebs
要是她可以变成一张沙发 我们会很感激
If she'd come back as a couch,we'd really appreciate it.
走吧，我带你回家
Come on. I'll take you home.
我跟你去 我也去
-I'll go with you. -Me too.
我有多余的蒲团
I got an extra futon.
你拽个屁啊，我们什么都没有
Dude,you don't have to brag. We got nothing here.
谨此纪念桃乐丝考夫曼
知道吗…这里真幽静
You know....It's peaceful out here.